A Guide to the Lydia Avery Coonley Ward Papers 1861-1922
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Lydia Avery Coonley Ward Papers 1861-1922
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5672-a
94+ items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1982 September 29.
Biographical/Historical Information
American poet, 1845-1944, known for her wide circle of literary friends and her encouragement of young authors.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists primarily of social notes to Mrs. Ward from authors, some artists, and musicians. Some concern her work for the committees on literature for children, and children's day at the Chicago World's Fair. Susan B. Anthony, Hamlin Garland, George F. Root, and Jane Addams are mentioned. Letters, works in progress, philanthropies, and family news are common topics.
A manuscript of "The Tower of Flame" by Richard Watson Gilder is included, as are autographs and letters collected by her.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
Contents List
- Lyman Abbott 1899 May 26 (Box 1)
- Oscar Fay Adams 1897 Nov. 28 (Box 1)
- Percy Alden 1896 Oct. 13, 1899 May 15 (Box 1)
- James Lane Allen 1897 Feb. 8 (Box 1)
- William Archer 1899 Apr. 19 (Box 1)
- C. R. Ashbee 1916 Mar. 13 (Box 1)
- Marion and Amelia Avery n.d. (Box 1)
- Amelia E. Barr n.d. (Box 1)
- Frederic Clay Bartlett 1922 Jan. 19 (Box 1)
- Clara D. Bates 1893 Aug. - 1894 Oct. 29, n.d. (Box 1)
- Henry Ward Beecher 1873 Feb. 15 (Box 1)
- Lilian Bell 1897 Jan. 1 (Box 1)
- Park Benjamin [1863]Aug. 3 (Box 1)
- Harriot Stanton Blatch [1900]Jan. 23 (Box 1)
- M. Boutet de Mouvel 1899 Jan. 29 (Box 1)
- Anna H. Branch 1917 Mar. 6 (Box 1)
- B. H. Bristow 1877 Apr. 3 (Box 1)
- John Graham Brooks 1896 Dec. 18 - [1900 Feb. 28], n.d. (Box 1)
- Noah Brooks 1893 May 26 (Box 1)
- G. W. Bungay 1863 Feb. 9 (Box 1)
- Hesekiah Butterworth [ca. 1893] (Box 1)
- G. W. Cable [1892 Jan. 12], 1896 Jan. 3 (Box 1)
- Helen Campbell n.d. (Box 1)
- Mary Hartwell Catherwood 1897-1900 (Box 1)
- J. V. Cheney 1895 Jun. 24 - Sep. 12 (Box 1)
- Kate Chopin 1898 Mar. 31 (Box 1)
- Frederic Horace Clark 1892 May 24 (Box 1)
- Albert Coates 1922 Jan. 22 (Box 1)
- Frances Power Cobb [1896] Jul. 9, 11 (Box 1)
- Robert Collyer 1897 Oct. 22 (Box 1)
- Sarah B. Cooper 1896 Jun. 21 (Box 1)
- Edward Gordon Craig n.d. (Box 1)
- F. Marion Crawford n.d. (Box 1)
- Martha Foote Crow [1898 Mar.] (Box 1)
- G. W. Curtis n.d. (Box 1)
- Abby Morton Diaz [1894] Aug. 31, Sep. 10 (Box 1)
- Anna E. Dickinson n.d. (Box 1)
- Mary Mapes Dodge 1882 May 29 - 1893 Mar. 31 (Box 1)
- Clarence Eddy 1893 Nov. 3 (Box 1)
- Edward W. Emerson 1892 Feb. 7 - [1903] Apr. 30 (Box 1)
- Ellen T. Emerson 1903 Apr. 29 (Box 1)
- Kate Field 1893 Nov. 16 - 1894 Dec. 12 (Box 1)
- J. Malcolm Fisher n.d. (Box 1)
- John Fiske 1891 Dec. 21 (Box 1)
- Horace Fletcher 1897 Jun. 12 (Box 1)
- B. O. Flower 1895 Apr. 20 (Box 1)
- [Benjamin?] Franklin (facsimile) n.d. (1785 Jul. 9) (Box 1)
- Henry B. Fuller 1896 Jan. 11 - 1915 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
- W. C. Gannett 1891 Sep. 2 - 1895 Nov. 8 (Box 1)
- R. L. Garner 1897 May 8 (Box 1)
- William Lloyd Garrison [Jr.] 1903 May 23, Nov. 5 (Box 1)
- R. W. Gilder 1893 Jul. 10 (Box 1)
- John B. Gough 1861 Nov. 14 (Box 1)
- Edward Howard Griggs 1919 May 9 (Box 1)
- G. Stanley Hall 1896 May 22, n.d. (Box 1)
- Caroline Hazard n.d. (Box 1)
- George D. Herron 1897 Dec. 16 (Box 1)
- John H. Heywood 1895 Jul. 10 (Box 1)
- J. G. Holland n.d. (Box 1)
- Helen Wilson Hopekirk 1893 May 19, n.d. (Box 1)
- Elizabeth M. Howe 1911 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
- Julia Ward Howe 1892 Dec. 19, n.d. (Box 1)
- David Irving [1891 Jan. 16] (Box 1)
- Be[?] Irwin n.d. (Box 1)
- Halsey C. Ives 1893 Sep. 6 (Box 1)
- Sarah O. Jewett [ca. 1894] Apr. 16 (Box 1)
- Rossiter Johnson 1897 Oct. 22 - 1899 Nov. 28, n.d. (Box 1)
- John M. Kapena n.d. (Box 1)
- Charles Rann Kennedy 1918 Nov. 27 (Box 1)
- George F. Kunz 1921 Sep. 21 (Box 1)
- Mary Day Lanier 1921 May 22 (Box 1)
- Lucy Larcom 1886 Nov. 30 (Box 1)
- Johann Leech [ca. 1848] (Box 1)
- Benson J. Lossing to George D. Prentice 1862 March 21 (Box 1)
- Charles F. Lummis 1901 Apr. 3, 1904 Aug. 23 (Box 1)
- Hamilton W. Mabie 1893 Jan. 18-1899 May 8, n.d. (Box 1)
- Percy MacKaye 1899 Jan. 9 (Box 1)
- Harrington Mann 1915 May 31 (Box 1)
- Edwin Markham 1918 Feb. 5, Apr. ? (Box 1)
- Edward S. Martin 1897 July 7, 13 (Box 1)
- Brander Matthews 1895 Feb. 17 (Box 1)
- [Cecile McAlister] [1920 Sep. 19] (Box 1)
- George B. McCutcheon 1909 Feb. 1 (Box 1)
- Emily Huntington Miller [ca. 1896] May 17 (Box 1)
- Harriet M. Miller (Olive Thorne) n.d. (Box 1)
- I. B. Millet 1893 Feb. 16, n.d. (Box 1)
- Enos A. Mills 1911 Dec. 17 (Box 1)
- Louisa Molesworth 1893 Feb. 5 (Box 1)
- Angela Morgan 1918 Dec. 12 (Box 1)
- Felix Morris 1894 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
- Louise Chandler Moulton n.d. (Box 1)
- T. T. Munger 1893 Aug. 26 (Box 1)
- J. S. Newberry n.d. (Box 1)
- Isaac Newton (Facsimile) n.d. (1705 Sep. 14) (Box 1)
- Christine Nilsson 1871 Jan. 25 (Box 1)
- Thomas Nelson Page 1893 Jan. 25 (Box 1)
- Alice Freeman Palmer [1901] (Box 1)
- William Ordway Partridge 1893 Mar. 28, Apr. 14 (Box 1)
- Mary H. Peabody 1893 Dec. (Box 1)
- Elia W. Peattie 1900 Jan. 21, Dec. 27 (Box 1)
- Bliss Perry 1907 Mar. 6 (Box 1)
- Carlotta Perry 1896 Mar. 17 - 1901 Mar. 21 (Box 1)
- Nora Perry 1886 Nov. 1 - 1896 Jan. 3 (Box 1)
- Edna Dean Porter 1895 Oct. 23 - 1896 Feb. 24 (Box 1)
- J. F. Raffaelli [1900 Jan.] (Box 1)
- John Sims Reeves n.d. (Box 1)
- Alice Hegan Rice 1918 Sep. 18 (Box 1)
- Laura E. Richards 1893, n.d. (Box 1)
- Abby S[age]; R[ichardson][1900] (Box 1)
- Emma Roache-Lamme 1894 May 2 (Box 1)
- Charles Rohlfs 1911 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
- William M. Salter 1892 Feb. 8, 1893 Feb. 6 (Box 1)
- F. B. Sanborn 1895 Jan. 27-1900 Jun. 12 (Box 1)
- Dallas Lore Sharp 1923 Oct. 29 (Box 1)
- Isabel Somerset [1892] (Box 2)
- C. H. Spurgeon n.d. (Box 2)
- Charlotte Perkins Stetson 1896 Mar. 27 - 1898 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
- Grace Ellery Channing-Stetson n.d. (Box 2)
- Idah M. Strobridge 1901 Apr. 2 (Box 2)
- Ruth McEnery Stuart 1895 Jun. 27 - 1899 Dec. 24, n.d. (Box 2)
- Charles Sumner n.d. (Box 2)
- David Swing 1893 Mar. 4 (Box 2)
- H.O. Tanner 1911 Oct. 2 - 1915 May 18 (Box 2)
- Winnie Louise Taylor 1895 Apr. 21, 1896 Jul. 6 (Box 2)
- Celia Thaxter n.d. (Box 2)
- Emma C. Thursby [1896] Jan. 20, n.d. (Box 2)
- Bradford Torrey 1893 Aug. 23 (Box 2)
- Martin F. Tupper 1866 Sep. 15 (Box 2)
- Camilla Urso 1893 May 2, 3 (Box 2)
- The Duchess of Veragua 1893 May 20 (Box 2)
- Swami Vivekananda 1893 Nov. 2 (Box 2)
- R. W. Vonnoh 1896 Jan. 10 (Box 2)
- Z. G. Wallace 1893 Oct. 20 (Box 2)
- Elizabeth Stuart Phelps Ward 1897 Jan. 29 (Box 2)
- E. F. Ware [1893]Jul. 21 - 1895 Aug. 20 (Box 2)
- Nettie Huntington Ware 1893 Nov. 16. (Box 2)
- Maude Radford Warren n.d. (Box 2)
- Henry Waterson 1877 Jun. 20, Nov. 3 (Box 2)
- Candace Wheeler 1893 Jan. 16 - [1898 Dec.] (Box 2)
- Lilian Whiting 1893 Nov. 2 - 1922 Nov. 6 (Box 2)
- Kate Douglas Wiggin 1892 - 1893, n.d. (Box 2)
- W. C. Wilkinson 1897 Feb. 12 (Box 2)
- W. A. Wilson 1886 Dec. 17 (Box 2)
- W. Windom 1881 (Box 2)
- [Prince Wolkowsky] [1896]Apr. 18 (Box 2)
- Henry Wood 1895 May 13 - 1899 Jul. 6 (Box 2)
- Mary E. Woolley 1911 Dec. 10 (Box 2)
- Madelene [Y. Wynne] [1893] Sep. 30 - 1899 Nov. 16 (Box 2)
- Ella Flagg Young and Laura T. Brayton 1916 Mar. 30 (Box 2)
- Unidentified (2 items) 1893 Sep. 20, n.d. (Box 2)